# **Odumosu Anuoluwapo Agnes**

3, Olubunmi Odumosu Street, Premiere Estate, Akuru, Oluyole Extension, Ibadan, Oyo State. 07033156893, 07013348414.

<u>anuoluwapoagnes@gmail.com</u> <u>www.linkedin.com/in/anuoluwapo-odumosu</u>

## **Career Overview**

A Lawyer with a unique blend of intrapreneurship and legal expertise. I have interests in legal compliance, corporate governance and company secretary services.

I am of the firm belief that a company ran in accordance with the code of good corporate governance and in line with best practices internationally would experience tremendous growth.

#### **Education**

Obafemi Awolowo University Ile Ife Osun State.

May 2015-August 2016

■ Master's Degree in Law **L.L.M** (Distinction)

## (Law of Corporate Management and Finance)

Nigerian Law School, Lagos.

2012-2013

■ Council of Legal Education Qualifying Certificate (**B.L**)

Obafemi Awolowo University Ile Ife Osun State.

2007-2012

■ Bachelor of Laws (L.L.B) Second Class Upper (2.1)

Negotiation and Conflict Management Group College (NCMG College).

Nov. 2012

Certification in Foundation and Associate Mediators Course.

Queens School Ibadan

2001-2007

West African Secondary School Certificate

## **Professional Experience**

## Legal Consultant Male Integrated Science Nigeria Limited August 2016 till date

- Providing advice on different legal issues.
- Actively involved in preparing and drafting authoritative legal opinions.
- Reviewing international contracts, local contracts and other legal documents.
- Identifying the most important issues that need to be sorted out on a priority basis in contractual negotiations.

# **Solicitor/Attorney** Royal Heritage Solicitors and Advocates Nov. 2017-April 2018 Ikoyi, Lagos State.

- Acted as the Company Secretary for the firm and commercial clients from banking, oil and gas, engineering and real estate sectors.
- Led the team on the Firm's Rebranding, Website Design and Social Media Strategy.
- Led the team on the Firms business development strategies both locally and internationally yielding to an increase by 30% over 3 months in the transaction department.
- Led the team in transaction department of the firm.

**Legal Associate** 

Siji Soetan & Co. Lekki, Lagos State. Dec. 2013 – May. 2015

- Legal Representations, Incorporations, Legal Advisory and Property Management.
- Legal Compliance and Company Secretarial Duties.
- Drafted and reviewed legal documents including commercial leases, sales contracts, and management agreements.

Legal Extern

S.P.A. Ajibade & Co. Ibadan, Oyo State.

June 2013 – July 2013

- Gained further exposure to the Nigerian Court System.
- Conducted research on several areas related to legal issued and assisted attorneys with legal work and the courtroom preparation.

**Summer Intern** 

Nissi Lexis Chambers,

June 2010 – Aug.2010

Ibadan, Oyo State.

- Greeting clients and visitors
- Proofreading legal documents
- Scheduling appointments and court proceedings.
- Scanning, photocopying, and filing documents.
- Organizing hard copy and electronic filing system.

## **Core Accomplishments**

- Endorsed on Linked in profile for Corporate Law Skill by **Ladipo Soetan** (Managing Partner at Siji Soetan & Co.) on the 25<sup>th</sup> of January 2017. **Siji Soetan & Co.**
- Firm's Assistant Compliance Lawyer for Chevron Corporation (2015) Siji Soetan & Co.
- Editor Jury Press Agency (2011 -2012)

Faculty of Law, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Osun State.

### Skills

- Excellent research and Advocacy skill, Computer and Internet Proficient.
- Outstanding Interpersonal Expertise and exceptional ability to adapt to ever-changing situations with High Performance Culture.
- Exceptional drafting Expertise with demonstrated ability to identify and troubleshoot critical issues.
- Quick thinker with the ability to communicate efficiently and effectively.

### **Membership**

- Member, Nigerian Bar Association (NBA)
- Accredited Member, Corporate Affairs Commission (CAC)

## **Personal Data**

- Date of Birth: 13<sup>th</sup> November 1991.
- Sex: Female.
- State Of Origin: Ogun State.
- Nationality: Nigerian.